webstar.biz 2016-12-03

# Data protection declaration

                                                                                      Data protection declaration
Data protection declaration
Preamble
   WellStar GmbH & Co. KG, District Court Berlin HRA 34621, with its registered office at Charlottenstraße
4, 10969 Berlin, Germany, is represented by its general partners Christian Wiesner
(hereinafter known as „WellStar“), and runs the vitality and social community portal webstar (hereinafter
known as „webstar“) under the domain www.webstar.biz and the linked subdomain.
   WellStar takes the protection of personal data very seriously and wants you to feel safe when visiting
the webstar site. We therefore assign great importance to data protection. The collection, processing
(including saving, changing, transferring, blocking and deletion) and use of your data is subject to the
prevailing data protection regulations.
   Hereafter we would like to briefly describe the principles on the basis of which your data is used:
1. Data collection and storage
   Within the scope of registering with webstar, WellStar collects and stores personal data about the
respective member and processes this i.e. uses this data for substantiating, carrying out and settling the
user relationship (hereinafter known as „registration data“). Personal data are individual details about the
personal or factual circumstances of a certain or identifiable person, such as, for instance, their first name,
surname, address, phone number, date of birth or e-mail address. The date of birth is primarily needed to
ensure that the member using webstar is at least 18 years of age.
   In order to be able to process and execute orders in the WellStar shop, WellStar also collects and
saves additional personal data such as the delivery address and details on the preferred mode of payment
(hereinafter generally referred to as ”ordering data”).
   For the purpose of creating their own profile on WellStar and presenting themselves on the portal,
members can, in addition to their registration data, provide further data and content about themselves. All
data and content which you provide to create your profile shall hereinafter be referred to as “profile data”.
   By using webstar, other data is collected about you, such as your body weight and size (hereinafter
referred to as “vitality data“). These details are provided voluntarily and serve to calculate your vitality
index, for example. Details you provide in your diary (dietary plans, fitness plans) help you to stick to a
disciplined routine and to calculate your vitality index. Responding to questions about your state of health
will help us to calculate your vitality index.

                                                                                     Data protection declaration
2. Publication
   WellStar makes your profile data partly or wholly visible to other webstar members within the members‘
area, depending on what your relationship is to them and what data you have displayed:
   What 			                     Friend			             Acquaintance
   Activities 			               X 			                 X
   Interests 			                X 			                 X
   Favourite music 		           X 			                 X
   Favourite programmes         X 			                 X
   Favourite films		            X 			                 X
   Favourite books		            X 			                 X
   Favourite quotations         X 			                 X
   about me 			                 X 			                 X
   Surname and first name       X 			                 X
   Profile image 		             X 			                 X
   Activity level 		            X 			                 X
   Vitality index 		            X      		             –
   Furthermore, other members can view data that you have published on other members’ profile pages
e.g. pinwall entries. These entries can be viewed by members you are connected with in the community,
on whose page you have placed an entry. Further provisions apply for members who are also sales
partners of WellStar. These can be found in the Declaration of Privacy for sales partners.
   It is possible to search for other members on webstar. Webstar members cannot be found on external
search engines such as Google. Not having a login or password, robots/crawlers used by search engines
cannot gain access to webstar, i.e. profile data is not displayed in external search engines. We cannot,
however, provide a guarantee for this.

                                                                                     Data protection declaration
3. Data transfer
   WellStar shall not pass on data for promotional or other purposes to third parties, unless this has
explicitly been stated in the Declaration of Privacy.
   Your registration, profile and vitality data are passed on to your personal vitality coach. Your coach is
obliged to treat the data they receive confidentially and to use it exclusively to provide vitality advice, and
to fulfil their contractual obligations.
   Your vitality coach is also automatically classed as your friend in the webstar community and can be
“downgraded” by you to an acquaintance.
   Within the scope of directly ordering goods from WellStar in the WellStar shop, it may also be necessary
to pass on your ordering data to the companies in charge of production and the delivery of goods, as well
as the bank responsible for the settlement of payments. They too are obliged to treat all data they receive
confidentially and to use it exclusively to fulfil their contractual obligations.
   WellStar enters into cooperation agreements with external providers, known as shop partners. These
shop partners are given personalised shops on the webstar sites. If you choose to make use of the offers
of shop partners, your ordering data will be passed on to the corresponding shop partners. Detailed
information on credit cards and account numbers will be collected directly by the respective shop partner
and hence not be conveyed by WellStar. The shop partners are also obliged to treat all data they receive
confidentially and exclusively for the purpose of executing their contractual obligations.
   In order to be able to provide an attractive range of products from our shop partners, our shop partners
regularly inform WellStar about which products you have purchased from the respective shop partner and
the amount you have spent.
   Furthermore, WellStar will only disclose your data to third parties in cases where there is a legal
obligation to do so. By using webstar, you agree to data about you being collected, processed and used by
WellStar in the aforementioned manner and for the aforementioned purpose.
4. Newsletters
   WellStar automatically sends newsletters by e-mail to remind you of your plans (e.g. fitness plans or
dietary plans). At your explicit request, you will receive a regular newsletter by e-mail with information
about new developments and current offers by webstar and WellStar.
5. General access data
   When using webstar or visiting the website www.webstar.biz, it is a standard procedure that general
access data is stored. Each of the records created in the process consists of one page from which the data

                                                                                        Data protection declaration
was requested, the name of the file, the date and time of the request, the volume of data transmitted, the
access status (file transferred, file not found, etc.), a description of the type of web browser used and the IP
address of the PC from which the request originated.
   The general access data is evaluated solely for statistical purposes and for the technical administration of
the website. There is no combining the general access data with the data listed under Item 1.
6. Cookies
   Webstar uses cookies. These are small text files that are stored on your computer and make it possible
to analyse your use of webstar. Different types of cookies are stored, e.g. for the autologin, as well as for
the identification of your browser and of the friends you have invited.
   You can prevent the installation of cookies by adjusting the settings of your browser software. However,
we would like to point out that it is possible that you may then not be able to make full use of all webstar
functions.
7. Google Analytics
   Webstar uses “Google Analytics”, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway,
Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”), which also uses cookies. The information created by the cookie
about the use of webstar (including the respective IP address of the visitor) is transferred to Google’s
server in the USA and stored there. Google makes use of this information to assess the use of webstar in
order to compile reports about the website activities for webstar or WellStar, as well as reports on the use
of webstar and of services provided on the internet in general. Google may disclose this information to
third parties if this is legally required or in order for third parties to process this data on behalf of Google.
On no account will Google associate your IP address with any other Google data.
   By using webstar, you agree to data collected about you being processed by Google in the
aforementioned manner and for the aforementioned purpose.
8. Use of data after deactivation, right of information and deletion rights
   The member may alter their profile data or deactivate their profile at any time. His personal data
will then no longer be available to other webstar members. His personal data will, however, be stored
after deactivation, so that access may in future be regained, especially in the case of a possible account
reactivation.
   Independent of this, you are entitled, according to Section 34 of the German Data Protection Act (BDSG),
to receive information from WellStar about the data WellStar has stored about you free of charge. In

                                                                                      Data protection declaration
accordance with Section 35 of the BDSG, you are also entitled to correct, delete or have this data blocked.
Any questions regarding this or the revocation of any consent given may be directed at any time to
   WellStar GmbH & Co. KG, Charlottenstraße 4, 10969 Berlin
   Phone: +49 (0)30 - 47 37 28 - 0
   Fax: +49 (0)30 - 47 37 28 - 11
   E-Mail: info@wellstar-international.de
9. External links
   Webstar contains links to third party sites, i.e. external links. Wellstar herewith explicitly refuses to be
held responsible for any contents found on these sites. These websites and their contents are subject to
the liability of the respective operator. When first establishing the link to the external sites, WellStar will
have examined the contents for possible infringements. Yet it has no influence on the current or future
design or content of the linked web pages. WellStar cannot continuously monitor external links, unless
there is concrete evidence of legal infringements. In the event of WellStar being informed of any legal
infringements on these pages, the links shall be removed immediately.
10. Right of Modification
   Wellstar reserves the right to modify these data protection provisions. The most up-to-date version can
be viewed at any time at www.webstar.biz.
11. Translation
   Legally non-binding translations have been included in these data protection provisions. Only the
German text in its present form is authoritative.
12. Final Remark
   You can only gain access to your personal profile settings after entering your personal password. Make sure
you keep your access data confidential at all times and close the browser window when your communication
with webstar has ended. You will thus be helping WellStar to handle your data responsibly and to protect it.
   Status: December 2010
